SUMMARY

Senior Research Scientist specialized in human-computer interaction (HCI) and health, with extensive experience in conducting *formative studies* to identify needs and opportunities; *iterative design and development* of novel methods and tools to support those needs; and *evaluations* to examine usage and develop design implications for future tools.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2021 - Present Senior Research Scientist

Evidation Health

2020 - 2021 Research Scientist

Collaboratively develops, conducts, and analyzes novel quantitative and mixed-methods studies to investigate health-related perspectives and behaviors and examine novel technologies, tailoring study design to project goals (e.g., market research, patient-centered design, efficacy evaluations).

Leads study document design (e.g., protocols, informed consent forms, survey / interview guides).

Consults with internal and external stakeholders to elicit and communicate relevant constraints.

2014 - 2020 Research Assistant

University of Washington

Investigated supporting people and their health providers in collecting, analyzing, and interpreting patient-generated data to meet personalized health goals in multiple health contexts.

Conducted surveys and interviews to characterize needs and opportunities in health contexts.

Collaborated with health providers in the design and evaluation of novel prototype health apps, including mobile apps and interactive, exploratory visualizations.

Research resulted in 14 peer-reviewed publications in top-tier human-computer interaction venues, as well as related grants from the NSF (\$500k) and NIH (\$1.5M).

More detailed descriptions available on my personal website.

Summer 2017 Research Intern

Microsoft Research

Conducted a feasibility study to investigate how a mobile app can support behavioral therapy.

Designed and analyzed surveys to: 1) characterize significant positive changes in anxiety, depression, and coping skill use; 2) develop a theoretical model to describe how the app supported these improvements; and 3) distill design implications for future tools.

Identified opportunities for machine learning techniques to provide personalized and context-aware suggestions to help people identify feasible and useful positive coping skills.

EDUCATION

2014 - 2020 University of Washington

Seattle, WA

Ph.D., Computer Science & Engineering. GPA: 3.9

M.S. earned 12/2016

Dissertation: Goal-Directed Self-Tracking in the Management of Chronic Health Conditions

Advisors: James Fogarty, Sean Munson

2010 - 2014 Pomona College

Claremont, CA

B.A. cum laude, Computer Science. GPA: 3.9

Skills

UXR Methods Semi-structured interviews, surveys, field studies, observation, contextual inquiry, RITE.

Data Analysis Qualitative data analysis (e.g., coding, thematic analysis, affinity diagraming);

Quantitative data analysis (e.g., R, Python, Pandas, NumPy, SciPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn).

Prototyping Prototypes, mobile and web app development (e.g., Angular, Ionic, D3.js).

Leadership Project management; communication (e.g., scientific and technical writing, presentations);

diversity and inclusion advocacy.

AWARDS & HONORS

2017, 2018 Best I	aper Award (CHI 2017) and Honorable Mentions	(CHI 2017, DIS 2018)
-------------------	----------------------	--------------------------	----------------------

NSF Graduate Research Fellowship Program Awardee
Marilyn Fries Endowed Regental Fellowship Recipient

2014 ARCS Foundation Fellow

2014 Harvey Mudd Computer Science Clinic Team Award Winner

2013 DREU-CRAW Participant

2013 Grace Hopper Scholarship Recipient

2010 - 2013 Pomona College Scholar

TEACHING, MENTORING, SERVICE, AND LEADERSHIP

Affiliate Assistant ProfessorCollaborating on research projects and mentoring UW PhD students (2021—Present)Research MentorMentoring Evidation interns and HCI students at UW and UCI (2020—Present)ReviewerCHI 2017-2021; CSCW 2018-2019; DIS 2018-2019; ACII 2021; IMWUT 2019.Teaching AssistantDesigned and graded assignments, critiqued projects, and advised UW graduate

students in CSE 510: Advanced Topics in HCI (Winter 2018, Fall 2018).

HCI Seminar Lead Led improvements to the Computer Science department's weekly HCI seminar and

organized quarterly themes, presentations, and feedback (January 2017—June 2018).

UW CSE GraduateCoordinated one-on-ones with faculty and current graduate students and organizedAdmissions Volunteersocial activity (Winter 2018); reviewed graduate student applications (Fall 2016).Orientation LeaderOrganized orientation for the new Computer Science graduate students (Fall 2016).Writing FellowWorked with Pomona students to improve their writing (Fall 2011—Spring 2014).

Senior Science Fellow for the 2013/2014 academic year.

SELECT PUBLICATIONS

Full publication lists available on my personal website and my Google Scholar Page.

J Schroeder, J Suh, C Wilks, M Czerwinski, SA Munson, J Fogarty, T Althoff. <u>Data-Driven Implications for Translating Evidence-Based Psychotherapies into Technology-Delivered Interventions</u>. *PervasiveHealth* 2020.

J Schroeder, R Karkar, N Murinova, J Fogarty, SA Munson. <u>Examining Opportunities for Goal-Directed Self-Tracking to Support Chronic Condition Management</u>. *UbiComp 2020*.

J Schroeder, J Fogarty, S Munson. <u>Personalizing Health Technologies to Support Patient and Provider Goals</u>. CSCW 2019 Workshop on Identifying Challenges and Opportunities in Human–AI Collaboration in Healthcare.

CF Chung, Q Wang, **J Schroeder**, A Cole, J Zia, J Fogarty, SA Munson. <u>Identifying and Planning for Individualized Change</u>. *UbiComp 2019*.

J Schroeder, R Karkar, J Fogarty, JA Kientz, SA Munson, M Kay. <u>A Patient-Centered Proposal for Bayesian</u> Analysis of Self-Experiments for Health. *JHIR 2018*.

J Schroeder, CF Chung, DA Epstein, R Karkar, A Parsons, N Murinova, J Fogarty, SA Munson. <u>Examining</u> Self-Tracking by People with Migraine. *DIS* 2018. Best Paper Honorable Mention.

J Schroeder, C Wilks, K Rowan, A Toledo, A Paradiso, M Czerwinski, G Mark, MM Linehan. <u>Pocket Skills: A Conversational Mobile Web App To Support Dialectical Behavioral Therapy</u>. *CHI 2018*.

R Karkar, **J Schroeder**, D Epstein, L Pina, J Scofield, J Fogarty, JA Kientz, SA Munson, R Vilardaga, J Zia. <u>TummyTrials</u>. *CHI 2017*. Best Paper Honorable Mention.

CF Chung, E Agapie, **J Schroeder**, S Mishra, J Fogarty, S Munson. When Personal Tracking Becomes Social. *CHI 2017*.

D Epstein, N Lee, J Kang, E Agapie, **J Schroeder**, L Pina, J Fogarty, JA Kientz, SA Munson. <u>Examining Menstrual Tracking to Inform the Design of Personal Informatics Tools</u>. *CHI 2017*. Best Paper Awardee.

J Schroeder, J Hoffswell, CF Chung, J Fogarty, S Munson, J Zia. <u>Supporting Patient-Provider Collaboration to Identify Individual Triggers using Food and Symptom Journals</u>. *CSCW 2017*.